<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://books.chrishubbs.com/feed.atom</id>
  <title>The Bookshelf: Chris's book log</title>
  <updated>2023-09-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Hubbs</name>
    <email>chris@chrishubbs.com</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/feed.atom" rel="self"/><entry>
      <title>Translation State</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/ann-leckie/translation-state/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:05ba5fba-1cb6-6b26-5e7e-775d1239c6a4</id>
      <updated>2023-09-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Translation State by Ann Leckie.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;A brilliant examination of gender and personhood wrapped up in an adventure story. Really enjoyed this one.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>The Ultimate Quest</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/jordan-haynie-ware/the-ultimate-quest/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:8f555533-ba3e-1ef5-352b-5be7226dd22c</id>
      <updated>2023-09-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading The Ultimate Quest by Jordan Haynie Ware.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;A short handbook intro to the Episcopal Church. The subtitle &amp;ldquo;A Geek&amp;rsquo;s Guide to The Episcopal Church&amp;rdquo; tells you where it&amp;rsquo;s going, and it goes HARD. Some of the geek references were helpful; some of them seemed pretty over-the-top, but you can&amp;rsquo;t deny the author&amp;rsquo;s commitment to the bit. Still, it&amp;rsquo;s a book I might hand to my college aged kid if they had any interested in attending.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>The Book of Job - a Biography</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/mark-larrimore/the-book-of-job/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:c0e9e150-8798-85f1-20f4-bf315731e8da</id>
      <updated>2023-08-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading The Book of Job - a Biography by Mark Larrimore.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a fan of other books in this Lives of Great Religious Books series, but this one didn&amp;rsquo;t really do it for me. Less about how Job came about and more about how it has been interpreted through time. Which isn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;bad&lt;/em&gt;&amp;hellip; just wasn&amp;rsquo;t what I was looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Until the End of Time</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/brian-greene/until-the-end-of-time/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:8afff93a-6de4-1c84-65d8-fa82945a79eb</id>
      <updated>2023-08-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Until the End of Time by Brian Greene.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;The bits where Greene is explaining physics are wonderful. The bits where he tries to theorize about how the effects of physics manifest in things like meaning and belief are pretty weak.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Being Heumann</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/judith-heumann/being-heumann/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:6364e60e-42e4-ed63-bf35-472426f89e84</id>
      <updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Being Heumann by Judith Heumann.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;A brisk, moving memoir of a leader in the American movement for disabled rights. I had no idea that the Americans with Disabilities Act wasn&amp;rsquo;t passed until I was in high school.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>How Far the Light Reaches</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/sabrina-imbler/how-far-the-light-reaches/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:070c4dde-d8a6-d0fd-25e5-e6a1c8aeeee4</id>
      <updated>2023-08-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading How Far the Light Reaches by Sabrina Imbler.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;A short memoir of sorts, fascinating stuff, beautifully written.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Birth of a Dancing Star</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/ilia-delio/birth-of-a-dancing-star/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:6e31cfdb-b914-db49-75d1-b4e36c1f76fa</id>
      <updated>2023-08-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Birth of a Dancing Star by Ilia Delio.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;As a review on Goodreads said, it&amp;rsquo;s a little more a recount than a memoir with an overarching theme and narrative. But it&amp;rsquo;s a great companion piece to Delio&amp;rsquo;s theological books; it provides a vivid perspective of the woman behind the ideas and words.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Breathing Under Water</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/richard-rohr/breathing-under-water/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:1d4cfb9d-6f2e-b7f7-8e8b-2d7ab29ef952</id>
      <updated>2023-07-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Breathing Under Water by Richard Rohr.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Rohr unpacks the Twelve Steps in the framework of the Gospel. Beautiful, simple, and helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Christ in Evolution</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/ilia-delio/christ-in-evolution/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:082d8332-c4c2-0c4c-de31-7570688f4c00</id>
      <updated>2023-07-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Christ in Evolution by Ilia Delio.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Delio says that Christianity&amp;rsquo;s cosmology needs to keep up with science, and explores through the writing of Teilhard de Chardin, Thomas Merton, Raimon Panikkar, and others just what that might look like. Mind bending in all the best ways.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Secular Faith</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/mark-a-smith/secular-faith/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:34126070-4742-56d3-e68b-cb8a15153409</id>
      <updated>2023-07-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Secular Faith by Mark A. Smith.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Smith argues from history that American religious beliefs largely eventually adopt broader secular trends. He uses topics like feminism and abortion as examples. The book was published in 2015 - would be very interesting to get his take now after the strong religious backlash and rise of Christian nationalist fascism since 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Trauma-Informed Evangelism</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/charles-kiser/trauma-informed-evangelism/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:64a9aa18-b56c-9412-f2dd-eb894aaf7f02</id>
      <updated>2023-07-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Trauma-Informed Evangelism by Charles Kiser.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;A good overview of spiritual and religious trauma and how Christians wanting to minister to the traumatized should approach the idea. The last couple chapters of practical application were particularly helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Babel</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/r-f-kuang/babel/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:3b4195a2-5caa-4c35-c6dc-927913ecdfeb</id>
      <updated>2023-07-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Babel by R. F. Kuang.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;A fantasy novel that serves as a strong critique of colonialism, a meditation on technology, and remains a moving story of adventure and friendship. The best novel I&amp;rsquo;ve read in quite a while.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Oscar Wars</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/michael-schulman/oscar-wars/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:2e6f62f7-8bd2-b96b-2572-62d626aaf06a</id>
      <updated>2023-06-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Oscar Wars by Michael Schulman.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;A well-researched an engaging tale of the Academy Awards throughout their almost 100-year history. Politics, personalities, cultural influences&amp;hellip; interesting to read about. Schulman makes this book an easy read while painting a vibrant picture of a messy industry.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Digging Up Armageddon</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/eric-h-cline/digging-up-armageddon/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:8bda8579-98de-289a-1869-ecb5d4b6910f</id>
      <updated>2023-06-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Digging Up Armageddon by Eric H. Cline.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;For an incredibly niche subject, this is a wonderfully interesting and accessible book. A history of the original archaelogial digs at Megiddo that happened in the 1920s and 30s. Chapters alternate between describing the people and their challenges and then the actual archaeological work. Good stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>The Book of Genesis</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/ronald-hendel/the-book-of-genesis/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:b7c3187c-1ac0-a66d-a8d0-0430cb5c41c0</id>
      <updated>2023-05-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading The Book of Genesis by Ronald Hendel.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;A delightful short excursion through the &amp;ldquo;biography&amp;rdquo; of Genesis examining the perspectives and interpretations of the church fathers, reformers, and philosophers up to the modern day. Very readable, and a nice introduction that takes a broader view than just the JEDP theories of textual criticism.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>The Morning Star</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/karl-ove-knausgaard/the-morning-star/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:ebad0f6f-9ce0-fe3e-7bd7-7ad901da3609</id>
      <updated>2023-05-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading The Morning Star by Karl Ove Knausgaard.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Ah, Karl Ove Knausgaard. I find his writing at once engrossing and dense. A bizarre multi-viewpoint novel that blurs the line between the living and the dead, with long excurses on the Christian perspective on death&amp;hellip; fascinating and baffling in equal measure. Not sorry I read it. Not at all.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Out of the Wreckage</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/george-monbiot/out-of-the-wreckage/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:5ed6c3f0-af9f-85e0-802f-df7845b6a27e</id>
      <updated>2023-05-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Out of the Wreckage by George Monbiot.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;An optimistic view of how the political system could be changed through the encouragement and organization of communities. Nice to read something hopeful for a change!&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Mystics and Zen Masters</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/thomas-merton/mystics-and-zen-masters/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:43302b1c-3b1f-ae30-d57b-6aac7704a91e</id>
      <updated>2023-05-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Mystics and Zen Masters by Thomas Merton.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Merton provides a sympathetic overview to both Western (Christian) and Eastern (Buddhist) mysticism. He sees them as far more compatible than I expect most Christian writers would. Interesting stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>The Mountain in the Sea</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/ray-nayler/the-mountain-in-the-sea/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:8e8dc414-5d30-d57f-a94d-8f9079cf49af</id>
      <updated>2023-05-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading The Mountain in the Sea by Ray Nayler.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Nayler really has two or three stories going here which are minimally intertwined. Unfortunately, this means he doesn&amp;rsquo;t fully flesh out any of them enough to make it a really great story. This book feels like it is in the vein of classic Michael Crichton novels - Jurassic Park, The Andromeda Strain, Congo&amp;hellip; but Crichton never let the details of science get in the way of writing a rollicking story. I feel like Naylor makes the opposite choice, and so instead we get a story with fewer scientific gaps, but also something less fun than a Crichton novel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would&amp;rsquo;ve loved to read a story that only took the octopus story line and evolved it quite a bit further. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Ordinary Monsters</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/j-m-miro/ordinary-monsters/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:09cbf1cc-0621-b332-6bb6-6c3ad92af88a</id>
      <updated>2023-05-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Ordinary Monsters by J. M. Miro.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Gothic supernatural horror&amp;hellip; overly long. A few interesting ideas but needed to be 300 pages instead of 550.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry></feed>