<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://books.chrishubbs.com/feed.atom</id>
  <title>The Bookshelf: Chris's book log</title>
  <updated>2024-02-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Hubbs</name>
    <email>chris@chrishubbs.com</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/feed.atom" rel="self"/><entry>
      <title>Ringmaster</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/abraham-riesman/ringmaster/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:167ff694-8d38-2ba3-5343-b3f8aaac94d2</id>
      <updated>2024-02-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Ringmaster by Abraham Riesman.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Painstakingly researched and grippingly told, this story of Vince McMahon&amp;rsquo;s life running the WWF kept me reading, and I care nothing for professional wrestling.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>In Universes</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/emet-north/in-universes/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:620f5892-1fb8-2ef8-4da8-d8107120ab86</id>
      <updated>2024-02-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading In Universes by Emet North.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Not fully sold on this one. I think I see what the author is trying to do, but there is too much disconnect in the middle chapters for it to hold together and make sense to me.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>The Murder of Professor Schlick</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/david-edmonds/the-murder-of-professor-schlick/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:09f2d717-0bd0-3ec0-b257-99eb2f338f38</id>
      <updated>2024-02-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading The Murder of Professor Schlick by David Edmonds.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;A remarkably engaging and readable introduction to the Vienna Circle and the dynamics in Vienna leading up to the Second World War.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Finding Zero</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/amir-d-aczel/finding-zero/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:1d3cf56b-6f01-fec9-dd29-5ad38a398d60</id>
      <updated>2024-02-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Finding Zero by Amir D. Aczel.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Less a treatise on ancient mathematics, more an adventure story of the author&amp;rsquo;s quest to find an ancient Cambodian stele with the oldest known inscription of the digit zero on it. Still, the guy knows how to tell a story.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>The Lost World of the Prophets</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/john-h-walton/the-lost-world-of-the-prophets/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:f0103f3c-3ff0-9d69-79d3-636038955fd6</id>
      <updated>2024-01-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading The Lost World of the Prophets by John H. Walton.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Dr. Walton continues his &amp;ldquo;Lost World&amp;rdquo; series with a focus on the Old Testament Prophets. The book is structured as a series of propositions, in each of which Walton advocates for a way we should think about Biblical prophecy. Readable even for laypeople, Walton is clearly trying to steer his audience away from a fundamentalist literalist reading, from a reading that directly ties all OT prophecies to much later fulfillments, and instead to understand prophecy as bringing a message from God that may have various interpretations and applications over time. Well worth a read.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Hell Is a World Without You</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/jason-kirk/hell-is-a-world-without-you/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:66c23237-00a9-a17a-4092-23b86dbd7606</id>
      <updated>2024-01-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Hell Is a World Without You by Jason Kirk.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Oh man. A coming of age story full of spiritual awakening, but an awakening that is more like deconstruction. Kirk captures the authentic inner and outer voices of youth growing up in conservative Evangelical circles, grappling with love, loss, and church teachings that just don&amp;rsquo;t make sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may not be for everyone, but it hits me right between the eyes, and makes me wish my awakening and deconstruction had come at 18 and not 38.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Varieties of Christian Universalism</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/david-w-congdon/varieties-of-christian-universalism/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:7177ac7e-27fb-fe34-958b-9ec5627dbd4d</id>
      <updated>2024-01-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Varieties of Christian Universalism by David W. Congdon.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Four chapters, containing four distinct perspectives on Christian Universalism. Some more familiar than others, all helpful as an exploration of various angles Christian theologians have taken in support of that view. Aimed probably a little bit above my head, but still manageable and accessible. The fourth option, Existential Universalism, was new to me and will have me thinking for a while.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>The Downloaded</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/robert-j-sawyer/the-downloaded/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:50091294-cbc5-3377-e680-3167f2bb2061</id>
      <updated>2024-01-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading The Downloaded by Robert J. Sawyer.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed a lot of Sawyer&amp;rsquo;s stuff, but this one left me cold. More a novella than a full-length novel, The Downloaded is entirely narrated in first-person interviews. There are a couple interesting technical ideas but they aren&amp;rsquo;t explored in enough detail to really be compelling. All in all, a disappointing book.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>The Kingdom, the Power, and the Glory</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/tim-alberta/the-kingdom-the-power-and-the-glory/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:17a16f0e-e08c-842d-2c0e-2f7768b5785d</id>
      <updated>2024-01-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading The Kingdom, the Power, and the Glory by Tim Alberta.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Journalist Alberta brilliantly evaluates and dismantles the corruption of American Evangelicalism. Having lived through it myself, I think he gets it right. May his tribe increase.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>The Case Against Reality</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/donald-d-hoffman/the-case-against-reality/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:73551bb1-3a69-4f68-497c-2856eb536375</id>
      <updated>2023-12-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading The Case Against Reality by Donald D. Hoffman.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;A very thought-provoking book and a great way to end my 2023 reading. Hoffman proposes that humans have evolved not to perceive the &amp;ldquo;objective&amp;rdquo; universe, but rather a view of the universe that is useful for &amp;ldquo;fitness&amp;rdquo;. So what, begs the question, is &amp;lsquo;objective&amp;rsquo; reality? Hoffman doesn&amp;rsquo;t have an answer for that question, but suggests that reality may be more defined by the interaction between conscious beings than by some objective &lt;em&gt;stuff&lt;/em&gt;. This goes down the same lines I&amp;rsquo;ve heard Ilia Delio suggest, that quantum reality is about the relationships between observers. Fascinating stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>The Collector</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/daniel-silva/the-collector/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:15cb5a9f-dad4-0dce-5486-10151e4f85d5</id>
      <updated>2023-12-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading The Collector by Daniel Silva.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Look, the Gabriel Allon series is fun, and Silva is a talented author. But he&amp;rsquo;s running into the same problem that all long-running series authors run into: you keep needing to up the stakes, and you end up with less and less reality. Inevitably, if your hero is in intelligence, you&amp;rsquo;re gonna save the world from nuclear destruction. Allon does. With typical aplomb. When you&amp;rsquo;re on book #23 of a series, I guess you&amp;rsquo;re not aiming for a lot of surprises.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Time's Mouth</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/edan-lepucki/times-mouth/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:c110322d-201d-2a2f-2fca-4e0f66a75876</id>
      <updated>2023-12-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Time's Mouth by Edan Lepucki.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;A story sort of about weird powers and the cult that forms around them, but sort of more about family, the burden it leaves us, and how we deal with it.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>The Helsinki Affair</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/anna-pitoniak/the-helsinki-affair/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:8a0b546d-f711-d4a8-b6a0-f9bb5a4369c4</id>
      <updated>2023-12-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading The Helsinki Affair by Anna Pitoniak.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;A easy read modern-ish spy thriller. Not as thrilling as some, but light and entertaining enough.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>My Old Home</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/orville-schell/my-old-home/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:4b83e26f-32b8-72ab-f57f-18456fb9d7b8</id>
      <updated>2023-12-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading My Old Home by Orville Schell.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;A beautiful, sweeping epic of life in China through the 20th century.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Making It So</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/patrick-stewart/making-it-so/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:8ad40b23-a506-bd94-9e45-c2ff5ed50237</id>
      <updated>2023-12-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Making It So by Patrick Stewart.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Sir Patrick&amp;rsquo;s memoir is just as delightful as you would hope. From stories about his humble beginnings in Yorkshire to tales about making ST:TNG, Stewart&amp;rsquo;s tone is engaging. I don&amp;rsquo;t typically do audiobooks but I would go listen to this one simply to hear the book in his own voice. A truly lovely book.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Titanium Noir</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/nick-harkaway/titanium-noir/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:38f6730f-cb59-91c1-9db0-e60c34553e8e</id>
      <updated>2023-11-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Titanium Noir by Nick Harkaway.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Cyberpunk hard boiled noir detective story. Entertaining stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>The New Being</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/paul-tillich/the-new-being/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:711c63fa-a4b8-4b76-0d46-cce0f1633ee4</id>
      <updated>2023-11-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading The New Being by Paul Tillich.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;A short collection of short sermons, a few of which are truly brilliant. &amp;ldquo;What is truth?&amp;rdquo; is one I need to revisit sometime very soon.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Girl One</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/sara-flannery-murphy/girl-one/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:48a16e40-b91b-9ff1-276d-6b89ac0d0172</id>
      <updated>2023-11-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Girl One by Sara Flannery Murphy.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;A little bit sci-fi, a little bit adventure thriller. An entertaining easy read.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>The Talmud</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/barry-scott-wimpfheimer/the-talmud/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:eeda6435-aa99-eafa-0941-9d2e123206d3</id>
      <updated>2023-11-16T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading The Talmud by Barry Scott Wimpfheimer.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed a lot of the Biographies of Ancient Books series but this one left me flat.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>The Testament of Mary</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/colm-toibin/the-testament-of-mary/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:a411791b-2f37-7ee5-3c00-e26771c019b6</id>
      <updated>2023-11-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading The Testament of Mary by Colm Toibin.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;A beautiful first-person narrative that considers Jesus&amp;rsquo; life from a different-than-usual perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry></feed>