<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://books.chrishubbs.com/feed.atom</id>
  <title>The Bookshelf: Chris's book log</title>
  <updated>2023-02-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Hubbs</name>
    <email>chris@chrishubbs.com</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/feed.atom" rel="self"/><entry>
      <title>The Three-Body Problem</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/liu-cixin/the-three-body-problem/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:48ccab7e-34a3-e56a-85be-fdb10754b278</id>
      <updated>2023-02-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading The Three-Body Problem by Liu Cixin.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;On re-read: still one of the most inventive sci-fi books I&amp;rsquo;ve read. Liu explores what interaction with an alien race of immense technology might be like, working at the quantum level as well as the interstellar. The first half of the book struggles to get going, but once the reveal happens and the book includes the alien civilization, the story comes alive.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>The Peaceable Kingdom</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/stanley-hauerwas/the-peaceable-kingdom/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:77f8cf59-0f43-b8fa-23bf-c410aecc490d</id>
      <updated>2023-02-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading The Peaceable Kingdom by Stanley Hauerwas.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s just a bit dated, but Hauerwas seems most focused here on non-violence among all the Christian ethic, and his heavy reliance on Yoder feels painful given what we now know about Yoder&amp;rsquo;s personal conduct.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Sanctifying Interpretation</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/chris-e-w-green/sanctifying-interpretation/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:394509d2-14e1-9fcd-be43-98b58a6c5f77</id>
      <updated>2023-02-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Sanctifying Interpretation by Chris E W Green.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;One of the most helpful theological books I&amp;rsquo;ve read in a long time. Green looks first at the Christian vocation for the sake of others, then at how Christians are called to holiness, and only then finally to how the Scripture may be interpreted in a way that works holiness within us for the sake of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really rich stuff, so much to chew on.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>The Passenger</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/cormac-mccarthy/the-passenger/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:b61d1292-d24a-8a8c-00a4-653383e74f1a</id>
      <updated>2023-02-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading The Passenger by Cormac McCarthy.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;On one hand, it feels like if I&amp;rsquo;m not rating a McCarthy book highly, it&amp;rsquo;s a shortcoming on my part, not his. And yet it doens&amp;rsquo;t feel like top-tier McCarthy. Still distinctly his voice, but not quite in the tier of his classics.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Heretic</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/jeanna-kadlec/heretic/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:bcea221f-bd84-b4d6-1a72-fd3dd4096299</id>
      <updated>2023-02-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Heretic by Jeanna Kadlec.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;If there was ever a time for a 3.5 star rating, this is it. The writing is uneven in spots - the first chapter, and near the end. It gets tight and compelling when she starts describing her first queer relationship, and at the end when she talks about finding community and interacting with Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some ways I&amp;rsquo;m very close to this story. Heck, my city and my employer are name-checked (rather unnecessarily) in the book. And in other ways I&amp;rsquo;m not so close. (My departure from the evangelical church wasn&amp;rsquo;t paired with any self-discovery about my sexuality.) What I resonate with here was the heartbreak of leaving the church, and what I jealously desire is the sense of community she has found in other places. (Will I ever find it?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the certain sort of reader who needs to know that leaving church is OK, this book is a godsend. For others it may be less than compelling.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Reparations</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/duke-l-kwon/reparations/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:40d4ab72-c48b-db08-64e0-31f216ea3c2e</id>
      <updated>2023-02-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Reparations by Duke L. Kwon.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Meticulously researched and footnoted, two evangelical authors making an impassioned plea to their evangelical compatriots to acknowledge the history of white supremacy in the US and move toward repentance and reparations. The fact that it fell on deaf ears is not the fault of the authors.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Don't Cry for Me</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/daniel-black/dont-cry-for-me/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:6814b6b5-76a1-6f5f-90f6-9ab257ee58a1</id>
      <updated>2023-01-31T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Don't Cry for Me by Daniel Black.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;A novel written as a series of letters from a black father to his son. There&amp;rsquo;s a huge amount of trauma being worked out in this book, both by the characters in the story and by the author who is writing this, per the Author Note in the front, as his own imaginative work of healing in his relationship with his father who is dying of Alzheimers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to think about with this one: generational and racial trauma, fathers and sons, hardened masculinity&amp;hellip; even as a straight white man it&amp;rsquo;ll have me thinking about my own father and how his and his father&amp;rsquo;s upbringing impacted his parenting. Phew.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Agent Josephine</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/damien-lewis/agent-josephine/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:4e1c4eff-54d9-db09-c8b1-3d4d192ece4d</id>
      <updated>2023-01-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Agent Josephine by Damien Lewis.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;This book tried to be too long with too little source material. The author (a British journalist) was working from 3 short books written by primary characters in the story, and with so little material he leaves us with nothing about Baker&amp;rsquo;s life before or after the war, and gives us large swaths of WWII history that have little to do with Baker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get the sense from the book that Josephine Baker was a remarkable woman, and I&amp;rsquo;d like to read a better biography of her.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>On The Soul and the Resurrection</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/saint-gregory-of-nyssa/on-the-soul-and-the-resurrection/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:5a29cf1f-94e8-84cc-c014-b12b13f4df0e</id>
      <updated>2023-01-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading On The Soul and the Resurrection by Saint Gregory (of Nyssa).

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;A lucid, short treatise from a 4th-century father. Very readable translation, too!&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Dead Lions</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/mick-herron/dead-lions/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:5489ff92-f31e-3eb0-70ba-a9877ed74b4e</id>
      <updated>2023-01-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Dead Lions by Mick Herron.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Second book in the series, similar to the first. A little bit oblique, written with a little more style than your usual pop spy novel.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>The Evolution of Knowledge</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/jurgen-renn/the-evolution-of-knowledge/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:fc87853e-9c23-443c-34be-a2587b205597</id>
      <updated>2023-01-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading The Evolution of Knowledge by Jürgen Renn.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;A thick book, Dr. Renn spends most of the time overviewing how human knowledge has accumulated over time. He spends frustratingly little time theorizing how those insights might lead us to think about the future. The &amp;ldquo;future&amp;rdquo; part is only about 15 pages at the end. I&amp;rsquo;m glad I read it just to stretch my brain, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t come away from it with any deep thoughts about the future.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Out of the Embers</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/bradley-jersak/out-of-the-embers/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:63ca7771-d7d2-2438-8e99-9139c22aff94</id>
      <updated>2023-01-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Out of the Embers by Bradley Jersak.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Jersak describes the experience of spiritual deconstruction and the path through it to something better in gracious, loving terms. Rich in grace and wisdom, filled with the assurance of God&amp;rsquo;s love, Jersak encourages those going through deconstruction to consider the words of (among others) Doystoevski and Simone Weil. The strongest bits of the book, though, are the first and third sections where he speaks pastorally to the challenged. Wonderful stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Still Just a Geek</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/wil-wheaton/still-just-a-geek/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:6cd14d8a-f29c-e194-25e3-30d614b0f2b5</id>
      <updated>2023-01-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Still Just a Geek by Wil Wheaton.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Wil Wheaton is one of those guys I just admire. He&amp;rsquo;s been so open about his challenges with his parents, his mental health, his career&amp;hellip; and equally so open about his love for his family and his care for others who struggle. His updated, annotated memoir is a combination of his old blog posts, narrative pulling it together, and copious, almost &lt;em&gt;Infinite Jest&lt;/em&gt;-ian footnotes. It&amp;rsquo;s a delight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making me equally happy is Wil&amp;rsquo;s assurance that Patrick Stewart, Jonathan Frakes, Levar Burton, Michael Dorn, Brent Spiner, and so many more from the ST:TNG cast are, in reality, as good if not better people than the roles they played on TV.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Every Good Boy Does Fine</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/jeremy-denk/every-good-boy-does-fine/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:e97fba9b-30b1-a9a1-4ec8-b4a9108c5acd</id>
      <updated>2023-01-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Every Good Boy Does Fine by Jeremy Denk.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;I love reading books by pianists. Mostly they remind me that while I&amp;rsquo;m a decent classical pianist, there&amp;rsquo;s a long step between me and a real, serious concert pianist. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Denk feels in some ways a little young to be writing a memoir like this. It&amp;rsquo;s really about his learning the piano and a little bit about him learning about life and about himself. It&amp;rsquo;s heavier on the piano teaching and technique than on the personal stuff, though the insights from his various teachers were interesting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; want to spend some time with the annotated appendix of referenced piano works to get familiar with some that are new to me.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>The Last Agent</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/robert-dugoni/the-last-agent/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:34bcb5b9-95cf-75f1-fd29-3029f95b6a89</id>
      <updated>2022-12-31T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading The Last Agent by Robert Dugoni.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;An entertaining spy novel, a genre which I hadn&amp;rsquo;t read in a while. Should&amp;rsquo;ve started with the first one but this one stood alone well enough. I&amp;rsquo;ll go back to the first one now, though, and fill in the gap.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Slow Horses</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/mick-herron/slow-horses/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:e08c0d33-484b-75d0-c539-60ad458a7849</id>
      <updated>2022-12-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Slow Horses by Mick Herron.

        

        

        

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Strangers in Their Own Land: Anger and Mourning on the American Right</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/arlie-russell-hochschild/strangers-in-their-own-land-anger-and-mourning-on-the-american-right/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:8a35b750-452d-d7c4-18c6-a9a008278631</id>
      <updated>2022-11-24T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Strangers in Their Own Land: Anger and Mourning on the American Right by Arlie Russell Hochschild.

        

        

        

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Changing Our Mind: Definitive 3rd Edition of the Landmark Call for Inclusion of LGBTQ Christians with Response to Critics</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/david-p-gushee/changing-our-mind-definitive-3rd-edition-of-the-landmark-call-for-inclusion-of-lgbtq-christians-with-response-to-critics/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:6d8decc2-09a3-4a13-e66c-4079daac2c67</id>
      <updated>2022-11-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Changing Our Mind: Definitive 3rd Edition of the Landmark Call for Inclusion of LGBTQ Christians with Response to Critics by David P. Gushee.

        

        

        

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>A Thicker Jesus</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/glen-h-stassen/a-thicker-jesus/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:d39e8698-75b3-9cdb-01af-dd834af527fe</id>
      <updated>2022-11-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading A Thicker Jesus by Glen H. Stassen.

        

        

        

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Destined for Joy: The Gospel of Universal Salvation</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/alvin-f-kimel/destined-for-joy-the-gospel-of-universal-salvation/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:10b2e314-030b-c816-7fd1-4555e052cb51</id>
      <updated>2022-11-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Destined for Joy: The Gospel of Universal Salvation by Alvin F. Kimel.

        

        

        

        
        
    </content>
    </entry></feed>