<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://books.chrishubbs.com/feed.atom</id>
  <title>The Bookshelf: Chris's book log</title>
  <updated>2023-06-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Hubbs</name>
    <email>chris@chrishubbs.com</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/feed.atom" rel="self"/><entry>
      <title>Digging Up Armageddon</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/eric-h-cline/digging-up-armageddon/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:8bda8579-98de-289a-1869-ecb5d4b6910f</id>
      <updated>2023-06-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Digging Up Armageddon by Eric H. Cline.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;For an incredibly niche subject, this is a wonderfully interesting and accessible book. A history of the original archaelogial digs at Megiddo that happened in the 1920s and 30s. Chapters alternate between describing the people and their challenges and then the actual archaeological work. Good stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>The Book of Genesis</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/ronald-hendel/the-book-of-genesis/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:b7c3187c-1ac0-a66d-a8d0-0430cb5c41c0</id>
      <updated>2023-05-30T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading The Book of Genesis by Ronald Hendel.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;A delightful short excursion through the &amp;ldquo;biography&amp;rdquo; of Genesis examining the perspectives and interpretations of the church fathers, reformers, and philosophers up to the modern day. Very readable, and a nice introduction that takes a broader view than just the JEDP theories of textual criticism.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>The Morning Star</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/karl-ove-knausgaard/the-morning-star/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:ebad0f6f-9ce0-fe3e-7bd7-7ad901da3609</id>
      <updated>2023-05-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading The Morning Star by Karl Ove Knausgaard.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Ah, Karl Ove Knausgaard. I find his writing at once engrossing and dense. A bizarre multi-viewpoint novel that blurs the line between the living and the dead, with long excurses on the Christian perspective on death&amp;hellip; fascinating and baffling in equal measure. Not sorry I read it. Not at all.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Out of the Wreckage</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/george-monbiot/out-of-the-wreckage/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:5ed6c3f0-af9f-85e0-802f-df7845b6a27e</id>
      <updated>2023-05-26T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Out of the Wreckage by George Monbiot.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;An optimistic view of how the political system could be changed through the encouragement and organization of communities. Nice to read something hopeful for a change!&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Mystics and Zen Masters</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/thomas-merton/mystics-and-zen-masters/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:43302b1c-3b1f-ae30-d57b-6aac7704a91e</id>
      <updated>2023-05-20T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Mystics and Zen Masters by Thomas Merton.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Merton provides a sympathetic overview to both Western (Christian) and Eastern (Buddhist) mysticism. He sees them as far more compatible than I expect most Christian writers would. Interesting stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>The Mountain in the Sea</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/ray-nayler/the-mountain-in-the-sea/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:8e8dc414-5d30-d57f-a94d-8f9079cf49af</id>
      <updated>2023-05-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading The Mountain in the Sea by Ray Nayler.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Nayler really has two or three stories going here which are minimally intertwined. Unfortunately, this means he doesn&amp;rsquo;t fully flesh out any of them enough to make it a really great story. This book feels like it is in the vein of classic Michael Crichton novels - Jurassic Park, The Andromeda Strain, Congo&amp;hellip; but Crichton never let the details of science get in the way of writing a rollicking story. I feel like Naylor makes the opposite choice, and so instead we get a story with fewer scientific gaps, but also something less fun than a Crichton novel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would&amp;rsquo;ve loved to read a story that only took the octopus story line and evolved it quite a bit further. Oh well.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Ordinary Monsters</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/j-m-miro/ordinary-monsters/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:09cbf1cc-0621-b332-6bb6-6c3ad92af88a</id>
      <updated>2023-05-12T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Ordinary Monsters by J. M. Miro.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Gothic supernatural horror&amp;hellip; overly long. A few interesting ideas but needed to be 300 pages instead of 550.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>All My Knotted-Up Life</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/beth-moore/all-my-knotted-up-life/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:5685a7a6-dc44-5d4c-d966-bbc46802066b</id>
      <updated>2023-05-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading All My Knotted-Up Life by Beth Moore.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;I mean, the memoir of a 60-something Baptist woman isn&amp;rsquo;t one of those books that a mid-40s exvangelical would be naturally drawn to, right? Beth Moore writes in her own unique voice, and it&amp;rsquo;s definitely memoir more than biography - spending lots of time in certain eras of her childhood, and barely skimming much of her adult life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That all being said, to add the knowledge of her personal story to her public persona is a great blessing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back before Twitter imploded, Auntie Beth was my favorite follow. Her clear love for Jesus and the Bible combined with her willingness to speak the truth even when it ran counter to her denomination and culture were such a dear example to all of us listening in. Getting this glimpse of her backstory only causes me to love her more.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>God on the Rocks</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/phil-madeira/god-on-the-rocks/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:7336abb8-f38d-b33e-0f46-aa441a5de365</id>
      <updated>2023-04-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading God on the Rocks by Phil Madeira.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;A sort of collection of short memoir-based essays&amp;hellip; Madeira recounts life growing up as a Baptist pastor&amp;rsquo;s kid, the pain of what we would today call religous deconstruction, and the joy of life. Nothing revolutionary, but not a bad read.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Hunting Time</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/jeffery-deaver/hunting-time/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:2f35c832-aec2-2cb6-b862-82290a9bdb95</id>
      <updated>2023-04-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Hunting Time by Jeffery Deaver.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Feels like a middle-weight Deaver book. I get that mysteries are supposed to have a twist at the end, but this one seems far too big and unbelievable given the beginning of the book. In addition, the early part of the story seems pretty bland, isn&amp;rsquo;t very twisty. Not bad, but not amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Tomorrow, and Tomorrow, and Tomorrow</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/gabrielle-zevin/tomorrow-and-tomorrow-and-tomorrow/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:f2b3d4b7-56e1-9d19-db4f-6eccf2281027</id>
      <updated>2023-04-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Tomorrow, and Tomorrow, and Tomorrow by Gabrielle Zevin.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Maybe more like 4.5 stars than 4. I didn&amp;rsquo;t just &lt;em&gt;adore&lt;/em&gt; the book, but I appreciated the characters and the conflict. A memorable, warm story in its own way.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Record of a Spaceborn Few</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/becky-chambers/record-of-a-spaceborn-few/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:3d6f60d8-fc50-7acb-702e-9dd34e0a284b</id>
      <updated>2023-03-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Record of a Spaceborn Few by Becky Chambers.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Becky Chambers invents a universe I would want to live in, and populates it with sympathetic, kind characters. In a genre that frequently gets dark and dystopian, she writes hopeful fiction. I need more of that.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>The Technology Trap</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/carl-benedikt-frey/the-technology-trap/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:7ffb7ee8-2e9c-19eb-a218-b99a61cdd243</id>
      <updated>2023-03-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading The Technology Trap by Carl Benedikt Frey.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;An interesting overview of the impact of revolutionary technology on society at large. In general, the recurring theme, says the author, is that people whose jobs are eliminated are worse off in the short run, but in the longer run everyone is better off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interesting to read his thoughts on the upcoming &amp;ldquo;AI revolution&amp;rdquo; as he wrote in the 2019 timeframe, prior to COVID, ChatCPT, and the like. Some of his predictions about the immediate ascent of AI have already flopped; others are certainly not moving as fast as he anticipated. Time will tell.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>A Closed and Common Orbit</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/becky-chambers/a-closed-and-common-orbit/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:e2fa27fd-44ce-c431-02d1-c091a53cfbde</id>
      <updated>2023-03-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading A Closed and Common Orbit by Becky Chambers.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Really should be 4.5 stars. Even more enjoyable than the first book in the series.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>A Hidden Wholeness</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/parker-j-palmer/a-hidden-wholeness/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:45d49299-ea2d-35ed-9227-c3845eb04f47</id>
      <updated>2023-03-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading A Hidden Wholeness by Parker J. Palmer.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Palmer sharing his wisdom and practical principles for operating a &amp;lsquo;circle of trust&amp;rsquo; - a principle where a small group of people care for each other primarily through quiet, acceptance, non-judgment, and loving, non-leading questions. An idea that speaks profoundly to me. Palmer makes me want to find and attend a Quaker meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Not All Who Wander (Spiritually) Are Lost</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/traci-rhoades/not-all-who-wander-spiritually-are-lost/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:08a1202b-7582-09a6-ffcf-9dc70518b5a3</id>
      <updated>2023-03-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Not All Who Wander (Spiritually) Are Lost by Traci Rhoades.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Flimsy, not particularly well written, and&amp;hellip; naive, maybe? Basically 150 pages of &amp;ldquo;yes, people go to different kinds of churches and sometimes move between them&amp;rdquo;. Not sure that qualifies as &amp;ldquo;wandering&amp;rdquo;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure who this book was aimed for but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t for me.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Art and Faith</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/makoto-fujimura/art-and-faith/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:dac261e3-f601-27a5-70d3-5cc4ba0704e9</id>
      <updated>2023-03-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Art and Faith by Makoto Fujimura.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;A world-class artist and thoughtful believer articulating the deep connection between artistry and faith. Beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>The Bayern Agenda</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/dan-moren/the-bayern-agenda/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:fe2d11bb-4397-801b-f0fe-77eab8e63ded</id>
      <updated>2023-03-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading The Bayern Agenda by Dan Moren.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Highly entertaining mixture of war adventure and sci-fi. Now I&amp;rsquo;m gonna have to read the rest of them.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Joel on Software</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/avram-joel-spolsky/joel-on-software/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:562f3426-17bc-0865-3f23-d8c6ffc6e3df</id>
      <updated>2023-03-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Joel on Software by Avram Joel Spolsky.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think I was reading Joel Spolsky&amp;rsquo;s blog at the time these pieces were originally published, but it was close. The programming and computer technology he&amp;rsquo;s talking about here is of course 20 years old and thus very dated, but his commentary on management and people dynamics is still spot-on and his writing is still entertaining.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Mindsight</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/daniel-j-siegel/mindsight/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:ef758ede-73e0-1f5d-fd28-e8e3b670bc47</id>
      <updated>2023-03-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Mindsight by Daniel J. Siegel.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Siegel is basically advocating a practice of mindfulness and emotional integration. The first half of the book is very solid, though it would&amp;rsquo;ve benefitted from getting rid of the foofy name. &amp;ldquo;Mindsight&amp;rdquo; makes it sound like a ridiculous pop self-help book. The second half of the book, primarily made up of case stories, is less interesting and beneficial.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry></feed>