<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://books.chrishubbs.com/feed.atom</id>
  <title>The Bookshelf: Chris's book log</title>
  <updated>2023-03-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Chris Hubbs</name>
    <email>chris@chrishubbs.com</email>
  </author>
  <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/feed.atom" rel="self"/><entry>
      <title>Record of a Spaceborn Few</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/becky-chambers/record-of-a-spaceborn-few/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:3d6f60d8-fc50-7acb-702e-9dd34e0a284b</id>
      <updated>2023-03-27T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Record of a Spaceborn Few by Becky Chambers.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Becky Chambers invents a universe I would want to live in, and populates it with sympathetic, kind characters. In a genre that frequently gets dark and dystopian, she writes hopeful fiction. I need more of that.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>The Technology Trap</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/carl-benedikt-frey/the-technology-trap/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:7ffb7ee8-2e9c-19eb-a218-b99a61cdd243</id>
      <updated>2023-03-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading The Technology Trap by Carl Benedikt Frey.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;An interesting overview of the impact of revolutionary technology on society at large. In general, the recurring theme, says the author, is that people whose jobs are eliminated are worse off in the short run, but in the longer run everyone is better off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interesting to read his thoughts on the upcoming &amp;ldquo;AI revolution&amp;rdquo; as he wrote in the 2019 timeframe, prior to COVID, ChatCPT, and the like. Some of his predictions about the immediate ascent of AI have already flopped; others are certainly not moving as fast as he anticipated. Time will tell.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>A Closed and Common Orbit</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/becky-chambers/a-closed-and-common-orbit/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:e2fa27fd-44ce-c431-02d1-c091a53cfbde</id>
      <updated>2023-03-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading A Closed and Common Orbit by Becky Chambers.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Really should be 4.5 stars. Even more enjoyable than the first book in the series.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>A Hidden Wholeness</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/parker-j-palmer/a-hidden-wholeness/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:45d49299-ea2d-35ed-9227-c3845eb04f47</id>
      <updated>2023-03-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading A Hidden Wholeness by Parker J. Palmer.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Palmer sharing his wisdom and practical principles for operating a &amp;lsquo;circle of trust&amp;rsquo; - a principle where a small group of people care for each other primarily through quiet, acceptance, non-judgment, and loving, non-leading questions. An idea that speaks profoundly to me. Palmer makes me want to find and attend a Quaker meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Not All Who Wander (Spiritually) Are Lost</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/traci-rhoades/not-all-who-wander-spiritually-are-lost/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:08a1202b-7582-09a6-ffcf-9dc70518b5a3</id>
      <updated>2023-03-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Not All Who Wander (Spiritually) Are Lost by Traci Rhoades.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Flimsy, not particularly well written, and&amp;hellip; naive, maybe? Basically 150 pages of &amp;ldquo;yes, people go to different kinds of churches and sometimes move between them&amp;rdquo;. Not sure that qualifies as &amp;ldquo;wandering&amp;rdquo;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure who this book was aimed for but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t for me.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Art and Faith</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/makoto-fujimura/art-and-faith/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:dac261e3-f601-27a5-70d3-5cc4ba0704e9</id>
      <updated>2023-03-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Art and Faith by Makoto Fujimura.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;A world-class artist and thoughtful believer articulating the deep connection between artistry and faith. Beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>The Bayern Agenda</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/dan-moren/the-bayern-agenda/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:fe2d11bb-4397-801b-f0fe-77eab8e63ded</id>
      <updated>2023-03-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading The Bayern Agenda by Dan Moren.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Highly entertaining mixture of war adventure and sci-fi. Now I&amp;rsquo;m gonna have to read the rest of them.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Joel on Software</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/avram-joel-spolsky/joel-on-software/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:562f3426-17bc-0865-3f23-d8c6ffc6e3df</id>
      <updated>2023-03-03T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Joel on Software by Avram Joel Spolsky.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think I was reading Joel Spolsky&amp;rsquo;s blog at the time these pieces were originally published, but it was close. The programming and computer technology he&amp;rsquo;s talking about here is of course 20 years old and thus very dated, but his commentary on management and people dynamics is still spot-on and his writing is still entertaining.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Mindsight</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/daniel-j-siegel/mindsight/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:ef758ede-73e0-1f5d-fd28-e8e3b670bc47</id>
      <updated>2023-03-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Mindsight by Daniel J. Siegel.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Siegel is basically advocating a practice of mindfulness and emotional integration. The first half of the book is very solid, though it would&amp;rsquo;ve benefitted from getting rid of the foofy name. &amp;ldquo;Mindsight&amp;rdquo; makes it sound like a ridiculous pop self-help book. The second half of the book, primarily made up of case stories, is less interesting and beneficial.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Fundamentals of Software Architecture</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/neal-ford/fundamentals-of-software-architecture/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:890ffe57-3f94-ea91-eb98-69d4fde9829a</id>
      <updated>2023-02-28T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Fundamentals of Software Architecture by Neal Ford.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;A little bit of work reading. A great summary of common software architecture patterns, their strengths and weaknesses.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Unmasking Autism</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/devon-price/unmasking-autism/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:5c2003f5-ab71-e9da-faca-bb4afe35a5eb</id>
      <updated>2023-02-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Unmasking Autism by Devon Price.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;A fantastic primer on Autism writen by an Autistic man. Very helpful as a neurotypical person to better understand and support Autistics around me.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>My Bright Abyss</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/christian-wiman/my-bright-abyss/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:fd844368-3fc0-1d08-2f4d-29d97320ed06</id>
      <updated>2023-02-23T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading My Bright Abyss by Christian Wiman.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Some really stirring stuff here. I often struggle with poetry but Wiman hits a sweet spot of poetry along with elegant prose.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>The Three-Body Problem</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/liu-cixin/the-three-body-problem/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:48ccab7e-34a3-e56a-85be-fdb10754b278</id>
      <updated>2023-02-19T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading The Three-Body Problem by Liu Cixin.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;On re-read: still one of the most inventive sci-fi books I&amp;rsquo;ve read. Liu explores what interaction with an alien race of immense technology might be like, working at the quantum level as well as the interstellar. The first half of the book struggles to get going, but once the reveal happens and the book includes the alien civilization, the story comes alive.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>The Peaceable Kingdom</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/stanley-hauerwas/the-peaceable-kingdom/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:77f8cf59-0f43-b8fa-23bf-c410aecc490d</id>
      <updated>2023-02-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading The Peaceable Kingdom by Stanley Hauerwas.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s just a bit dated, but Hauerwas seems most focused here on non-violence among all the Christian ethic, and his heavy reliance on Yoder feels painful given what we now know about Yoder&amp;rsquo;s personal conduct.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Sanctifying Interpretation</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/chris-e-w-green/sanctifying-interpretation/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:394509d2-14e1-9fcd-be43-98b58a6c5f77</id>
      <updated>2023-02-17T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Sanctifying Interpretation by Chris E W Green.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;One of the most helpful theological books I&amp;rsquo;ve read in a long time. Green looks first at the Christian vocation for the sake of others, then at how Christians are called to holiness, and only then finally to how the Scripture may be interpreted in a way that works holiness within us for the sake of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really rich stuff, so much to chew on.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>The Passenger</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/cormac-mccarthy/the-passenger/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:b61d1292-d24a-8a8c-00a4-653383e74f1a</id>
      <updated>2023-02-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading The Passenger by Cormac McCarthy.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;On one hand, it feels like if I&amp;rsquo;m not rating a McCarthy book highly, it&amp;rsquo;s a shortcoming on my part, not his. And yet it doens&amp;rsquo;t feel like top-tier McCarthy. Still distinctly his voice, but not quite in the tier of his classics.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Heretic</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/jeanna-kadlec/heretic/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:bcea221f-bd84-b4d6-1a72-fd3dd4096299</id>
      <updated>2023-02-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Heretic by Jeanna Kadlec.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;If there was ever a time for a 3.5 star rating, this is it. The writing is uneven in spots - the first chapter, and near the end. It gets tight and compelling when she starts describing her first queer relationship, and at the end when she talks about finding community and interacting with Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some ways I&amp;rsquo;m very close to this story. Heck, my city and my employer are name-checked (rather unnecessarily) in the book. And in other ways I&amp;rsquo;m not so close. (My departure from the evangelical church wasn&amp;rsquo;t paired with any self-discovery about my sexuality.) What I resonate with here was the heartbreak of leaving the church, and what I jealously desire is the sense of community she has found in other places. (Will I ever find it?)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the certain sort of reader who needs to know that leaving church is OK, this book is a godsend. For others it may be less than compelling.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Reparations</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/duke-l-kwon/reparations/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:40d4ab72-c48b-db08-64e0-31f216ea3c2e</id>
      <updated>2023-02-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Reparations by Duke L. Kwon.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;Meticulously researched and footnoted, two evangelical authors making an impassioned plea to their evangelical compatriots to acknowledge the history of white supremacy in the US and move toward repentance and reparations. The fact that it fell on deaf ears is not the fault of the authors.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Don't Cry for Me</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/daniel-black/dont-cry-for-me/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:6814b6b5-76a1-6f5f-90f6-9ab257ee58a1</id>
      <updated>2023-01-31T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Don't Cry for Me by Daniel Black.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;A novel written as a series of letters from a black father to his son. There&amp;rsquo;s a huge amount of trauma being worked out in this book, both by the characters in the story and by the author who is writing this, per the Author Note in the front, as his own imaginative work of healing in his relationship with his father who is dying of Alzheimers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot to think about with this one: generational and racial trauma, fathers and sons, hardened masculinity&amp;hellip; even as a straight white man it&amp;rsquo;ll have me thinking about my own father and how his and his father&amp;rsquo;s upbringing impacted his parenting. Phew.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry><entry>
      <title>Agent Josephine</title>
      <link href="https://books.chrishubbs.com/damien-lewis/agent-josephine/" rel="alternate"/>
      <id>urn:uuid:4e1c4eff-54d9-db09-c8b1-3d4d192ece4d</id>
      <updated>2023-01-29T00:00:00Z</updated>
      <content type="html">I finished reading Agent Josephine by Damien Lewis.

        

        

        &lt;p&gt;This book tried to be too long with too little source material. The author (a British journalist) was working from 3 short books written by primary characters in the story, and with so little material he leaves us with nothing about Baker&amp;rsquo;s life before or after the war, and gives us large swaths of WWII history that have little to do with Baker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I get the sense from the book that Josephine Baker was a remarkable woman, and I&amp;rsquo;d like to read a better biography of her.&lt;/p&gt;

        
        
    </content>
    </entry></feed>